I'd like to say welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel
and God spake all these words saying I
am the Lord thy God which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt out of the
house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the
iniquities of the fathers upon the
children, unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me, and
showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that take of his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Six days shall thou labor
and do all thy work. But the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shall not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man
servant, nor thy maid, servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill.
Thou shall not commit adultery. Thou
shall not steal. Thou shall not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shall not cover thy neighbor's house.
Thou shall not cover thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. We
read Exodus 21-17. And may the Lord have
a blessing to the reading of his words.
In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Amen. Amen. So here on question and
answer, you can ask us a question and
we'll answer it according to the King
James Bible. And if we cannot find the
answer, we will seek further counsel to
bring you an answer at a later time. The
questions we will not answer are the
vague and along scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream and
you may begin to send in your questions
at this time. Even questions that
pertain to everlasting life, we just
asking that you keep them to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. Got brother Jerome. Rest
in peace. Got brother Dre. Good evening.
Brother Julius. Good evening everybody.
Brother Tanzel, good evening. Sister
Deborah, good evening. Brother Sean,
good evening. And we have the guest
caller with us and I'm brother Cornell.
What is our first question of the
evening? Uh, yes, there are several held
over questions that will be answered
first before getting into tonight's Q&A.
So Renee Israel asks in Revelations
12:6, "Who is they that should feed the
woman Israel three and a half years in
the wilderness, the place of safety?"
All right. So, uh, Brother Jerome, can
you explain a little bit of that?
Let's go, um, read it. Um, Revelations
12:6.
And the woman fled unto the wilderness
where she hath a place prepared of God
that they should feed her there
1,23 score
days. Okay.
So, um, the Lord just like in the past,
you know, he the one that's going to
supply this woman, which is the church
that fled that flee into the wilderness,
the children of Israel and among other
nations that be that go in there with
them. Okay? But the Lord is going to do
it and and and he uses
angels to do it just like he did in the
past. Okay? So, let's uh look at some
examples of that. Let's go to uh
Exodus the 16th chapter and then we'll
do Psalms 91 after
that. Exodus 16, read verse 4-8 and then
we going to
skip. When you get it, go ahead.
Then said the Lord unto Moses, "Behold,
I will rain bread from heaven for you,
and the people shall go out and gather a
certain rate every day, that I may prove
them whether they will walk in my law or
no." And it shall come to pass that on
the sixth day they shall prepare that
which they bring in, and it shall be
twice as much as they gather daily.
And Moses and Aaron said unto all the
children of Israel, "At evening then ye
shall know that the Lord have brought
you out from the land of Egypt. And in
the morning then ye shall see the glory
of the Lord, for that he hearth your
murmuring against the Lord. And what are
we that ye murmur against us?"
And Moses said, "This shall be when the
Lord shall give you in the evening flesh
to eat, and in the morning bread to the
full, for that the Lord hear your
murmmory, which ye murmured against
him." And what are we? Your murmuring
are not against us, but against the
Lord. Okay, skip down and read verse um
13- 15.
And it came to pass that at at the
evening the quails came up and covered
the camp. And in the morning the dew
laid round about the host. And when the
dew that laid was gone up, behold, upon
the face of the wilderness, there laid a
small round thing as small as the hor
frost of the ground.
And when the children of Israel saw it,
they said one to another, it is mana.
For they wish not what it was. And Moses
said unto them, "This is the bread which
the Lord hath given you to eat." Yeah.
Yeah. And so, you know, the Lord was
feeding them then. He going he going to
feed the
people in the future when they go in
that when they flee into that
wilderness. Okay. Now, let's go to
91 and show you he going to have his
angels charge over the people when they
in that wilderness during that time.
Okay. Psalms 91. Just read verse one. We
going to skip and read verse 10 and 11
and that'll be it.
But he that dwelleth in the secret place
of the most high shall abide under the
shadow of the almighty. And this secret
place is referring to the uh wilderness.
Skip down and read verse 10 and 11.
There shall no evil befall thee, neither
shall any plague come n thy dwelling.
But he shall give his angels charge over
thee to keep thee in all thy ways.
Um, that's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question. As we
move on to our next,
uh, next question. Ash Mark Ash says,
"Would turning on the furnace to heat
your house be the same as using a
microwave, stove, or toaster to warm,
not cook your food? Since kindling of
fire is the
wilderness is Since kindling of fire in
the wilderness is work. Exodus 35 verse3
is given.
All right. So we know that that's
leaning toward even though you asked
that question that dealing with the
Sabbath day as well. But I see that you
mentioned all these different
appliances. So, you know, on the Sabbath
day, you know, the Lord told us that
it's supposed to be holy unto us and we
not supposed to be doing our own
pleasure or finding our own ways. But as
far as the furnace is concerned to heat
your house. That's what we have a
furnace for. Some people have a furnace,
gas furnace. Some people have a boiler.
If you don't heat your house in the
winter time, you risk your pipes
busting. Now you got a bigger problem.
You got people in the house that are
cold and freezing. He might have babies
there. So that's totally different. And
then you mentioned about the microwave
and me and brother Julius always say,
"What's the last name of microwave?"
Oven, right, Julius? Oven. That's right.
So that's another thing. Then you talk
about the stove. These are things that
you don't have to use on God's Sabbath
day. Remember, this is holy unto the
Lord. And he wants you to do it exactly
the way he say do it. And that go for
your toaster. I don't care if you warm
in your food. You don't need it on the
Sabbath day. The things that you do the
other six days when you coming to the
Lord's Sabbath, hey, don't do it. And
when you keep it the way the Lord says,
great reward in that. Let's go to Exodus
35. Exodus the 35th.
John because it can be done very
easily. Exodus
35 and let's pick it up in that verse
one. When you get there, Tanzel, go
ahead. And Moses gathered all the
congregation of the children of Israel
together, and said unto them, These are
the words which the Lord hath commanded
that ye should do
them. Six days shall work be done, but
on the seventh day there shall be to you
a holy day, a Sabbath of rest to the
Lord. Whosoever doeth work therein shall
be put to death. So we see that these
are the words which the Lord have
commanded. These are not the suggestions
the Lord commanded for it to be done
this way. What does verse three say? Ye
shall kindle no fire throughout your
inhabitations upon the Sabbath day. So
you don't kindle no fire throughout your
habitations on the Sabbath day. Now I
know you talking about a it's a fire
inside of your furnace. That's totally
different because if that go out then
your house can possibly fill up with
gas. You don't want that either. So,
look, just don't use these appliances
that you mentioned here on the Sabbath
day. Eat something that doesn't require
that. Turn over to Exodus 16. Exodus
16. And Lord going to show you how to
plan. So, you should be planning on
Friday to not have to use these things
on Saturday except for your furnace.
That's totally
different. And your water heater.
pick it up at that verse uh 11 and we
going to skip Exodus 16 and 11. Go
ahead, brother.
And the Lord spake unto Moses saying,
Here we go again with the Lord speaking
unto Moses. What he said verse 22. And
it shall come to pass that on the sixth
day they gathered twice as much bread.
Two for one man and all the rulers of
the congregation came and told Moses.
Yeah. And he said unto them, "This is
that which the Lord hath said, tomorrow
is the rest of the holy Sabbath unto the
Lord. Now bake that which ye will bake
today, and see that ye will seek that
that and that which remainth overlay up
for you to be kept until the morning."
So the Lord is saying here, hey, on your
Friday before the Sabbath day, you can
use your microwave oven and your stove
and your toast and all that, but he want
you to prepare enough so you don't have
to do it on the Sabbath day because the
Lord want you to rest and chill. Go
ahead,
brother. And they laid it up till the
morning as Moses ba, and it did not
stink, neither was there any worms
therein. Mhm. And Moses said, "Eat that
today, for today is a Sabbath unto the
Lord. Today you shall not find it in the
field." So six days you shall gather it,
but on the seventh day, which is the
Sabbath, in it there shall be none. So
you suppose on the sixth day, gather
twice as much bread. I'mma gather enough
for tomorrow, too, so I don't have to
use my microwave, oven, stove I already
prepared. Go ahead, brother. And it came
to pass that there went out some of the
people on the seven days for together
and they found none.
The Lord said unto Moses, "Well, how
long refuse ye to keep my commandments
and my laws?"
Yeah. So Lord is saying here that hey
they some people still went out on the
seventh day and when he gather some
bread anyway after they were told to
gather a double amount on the sixth day,
they still went out on the seventh. And
the Lord said, "How long refuse ye to
keep my commandments and my laws?" So
these things that you asked about, "Hey,
don't use them. Prepare your food on
Friday enough for two days and that's
all I got."
I want to interject something. Yes, sir.
He's talking about your funds in your
house. You know, when Jesus healed that
man on the Sabbath day, he asked a
question. Mhm. How many
Ox has fallen well on the Sabbath day
and you won't get him up. Can somebody
read that? Find that.
All right. Well, search mode for that.
Is it Luke 14?
Uh Luke, what verse? What chapter? Let
me take a look. I think it's Luke 14.
Let's see there. Luke
five. Luke 14 verse 5. Yeah, that's it,
brother.
So yeah, pick it up at the um at the
one.
Yeah, go ahead.
Go
ahead. Pick it up. And it came to pass
as he went into the house of one of the
chief Pharisees to eat bread on the
Sabbath day that they watched him. And
behold, there was a certain man before
him which had the drop seed. And Jesus
answering spake unto the lawyers and
Pharisees, saying, "It is lawful to heal
on the Sabbath day." And they held their
peace. And he took him and healed him
and let him go, and answer them, saying,
"Now, which of you shall have an ass or
an ox fall into a penny when I
straightway pull him out on the Sabbath
day?" And they could not answer him
again to these things.
Now, the reason the reason I went there
is because heating uh in winter time is
something that's
necessary because like you said, you can
lose your fights or somebody could be
sick, get sick from it, you know, right?
So, something that you uh uh uh that uh
uh you might try and uh uh not do, but
it create bigger consequences.
That ain't no pleasure.
Neither is it like kindling the fire.
It's just that in the same vein, your ox
or your ass are fell in the well on the
Sabbath day. Now, if you don't get him
up out of the well, he going to drown.
You going to lose your ox or your ass
and you going to pollute the water.
Yeah. certain things like
that's then that's just like your aunt
or your ass falling in the well on the
Sabbath day because if you cut it off
you're going to suffer other
consequences. That's all I have to say.
All right. Thank you for that add- on.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one. Next question.
Brother Anthony Horsey says, "Can you
shed some light on Mark 16 verse1 17?
What are new tongues? I thought speaking
in tongues only means speaking other
languages. Please explain.
All right, brother Julius. So can you
shed some light about the tongues? Yeah,
speaking in tonesues, what the world
calls speaking in tongues
is kind of like babbling. The real name
of it is glossalia. But when the book
talk about speaking new tongues, that's
generally talking about speaking the
language of your captivity or wherever
you are
scattered. Let me show you what I'm
talking about. Let's go to Mark the 16th
chapter and read that scripture. Mark
the 16th scap chapter, Tenzel. But this
time, we're not going to start at 17.
We're going to start at 15. And we're
going to pay attention to what we're
reading. And let's look what Jesus
commissioned his disciples to
do. Mark
16 and 15. Watch this right here. Go
ahead T. And he said unto them, "Go ye
into all the world and preach." Now hold
it right there. Go ye into all the
world. Told his disciples, right? Go ye
into all the world. Go ahead. and preach
the gospel of every creature. Now, you
can't go into all the world and preach
just Hebrew. You have to understand the
languages of those people in most cases.
Man, now give me verse 17.
And these signs shall follow them that
believe. And as you preaching the
gospel, people that believe in what
you're teaching and preaching and
understand it, go ahead. In my name
shall they cast out devils. Yeah, they
shall speak with new tongues. They shall
speak with new tongues. Tongues is
languages, sisters and brothers. But let
me show you new tongues. Let's go to
Acts the 2 chapter on the day of
Pentecost. And this is what popular
Christianity don't
understand. Acts chapter 2. And when you
get in Tanzanel, Acts chapter 2 and pick
it up at verse one. We gonna skip
because we got to read just a little
bit. Acts 2 and one. Go ahead, brother.
And when the day of Pentecost was fully
come, they were all with one accord in
one place. Now these are the disciples.
It was 120 in the upper room on the day
of Pentecost because Jesus had
instructed them, "Go ye and stay there
until uh the spirit of the Holy Spirit
come unto you." Verse four.
And they were all filled with the Holy
Ghost and began to speak with other
tongues as the spirit gave them
utterance as the spirit or the angel in
that case interpreted for them. And they
were all filled with the Holy Ghost and
began to speak with other tongues. These
are new tongues right here. And the
spirit gave them utterance. Continue in
five. And there were dwelling at
Jerusalem Jews, devout men out of every
nation under heaven. Oh, go ye into all
the world. These Jews were dwelling in
from places at Jerusalem because you
have to meet in Jerusalem to keep the
feast of Pentecost. Wherever you came
from, you spoke the language of the land
wherein you grew up in, where you were
born in. I was born in the United States
in Arkansas. I speak English. That's the
language of my captivity. Go ahead, my
brother. And when the Go ahead. And when
this was noise abroad, the multitude
came together and were confounded
because that every man heard them speak
in his own language. In the language
wherever they came from, these are what
the people were speaking. The disciples
were speaking. All these people that
came from every nation up under heaven,
you can read the whole thing on your
own. And look what verse seven. Read
quick. And they were all amazed and
marvel saying one to another. Behold,
are not all these which speak Galileans?
Uh-huh. That's talking about the
disciples because they from Peter. They
were from the area of Galilee. But they
were Jews from every nation. Read
brother quick. And how we every man in
our own tongue wherein we were born.
Why? Because the spirit gave them
utterance. Go ahead. Parththeians and
me. Parththeians and me. So these are
people up in Russia. People up in Partha
areas of Greece. Go ahead. and the
dwellers in Mesopotamia. Mesopotamia,
that's Babylon. Go ahead. And in Judea,
that's Jerusalem.
Capidoshia. Go ahead. And Pontius and
Asia. Go ahead, T. Persia and Panilia
and Egypt and in the parts of Libya
about Serene and strangers of Rome, Jews
and Proit. Uhhuh. Creeks and Arabians.
We do hear them speak in our tongues the
wonderful works of God. And this what
they were speaking in new tongue in the
tongues of where they were came from the
countries and the areas where they came
from. That's why Jesus said, "Go you to
all the world." Why? So when they were
scattered, they spoke the language of
wherever they was, right? Paul was the
apostle to the to the uh Gentiles. So he
was
multilingual. So that's all that is. New
tongues is the language of your
captivity or wherever you were born at.
That's all I got on that. I hope that
helped.
Something. Yes sir.
There's a spiritual side to it too that
goes beyond just conversation. I mean
speaking in a foreign language. Yes. I
said when you when you uh uh come into
the word and start get some
understanding and start serving God,
your conversation change even though
it's the same language. And just like
Paul was talking about how he died, you
know, let's let's have a quick look at
something here. Let's go to Romans the
7th chapter. Yes, sir.
And we're going to start reading at
verse 7.
Romans 77.
Mhm.
What shall we say then? Is the law sin?
God forbid. But nay, I have not known
sin, but by the law. For I have not
known lust, except the law has said,
thou shalt not coveret.
But sin taken by the commandments
wrought in me all manner of
concupitence. For without the law sin
was dead.
Uhhuh. For I was alive without the law
once. But when the commandments came,
sins revived and I died.
The commandments die.
Did Paul die? No.
He changed. Right. Okay.
Yeah. and keep a little more. And the
commandments which was ordained to life,
I found to be unto
death. For sin taken, by the
commandments deceive me, and by it slew
me. But wherefore the law was holy, and
the commandments holy and just and good.
Paul said that the commandment slew him.
It didn't kill him. What he did was he
killed the old Paul. Right. And the
conversation that Paul used to have, he
didn't talk that way no more. Even
though he talk the same
language. You understand? Yes, sir.
Just want I just that's just a spiritual
side to it. Like the stuff I used to
talk about when I was in the world, I
don't even dare talk that when since
I've been in the word of God. That is
right. Yes, sir.
So that old that old uh uh uh uh guest
speaker died and the new guest speaker
speaks on what thus said the Lord
instead of what thus said the brothers
and the sisters on the corner. Same
language but a
different way of talking. That's all
they have to say. Yes sir. That's what
that word of God does. Does it converse
you?
That's it.
All right. All right. Hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next.
Moving on. Uh Ni Jones have two
questions. One, at Christ's second
coming, when his feet touch Mount Si,
will it be us or the angels coming with
him? And two, in Matthew's 24
6-8, it talks about birth pains. When
does this happen?
All right, the first question deals with
that Christ second coming when his feet
touched at Mount Si. Will it be us or
the angels coming with him? And that
second part of the question, the guest
caller will take it from there.
Oh, okay. The second quarter part of the
question,
uh, I'mma look at that first because
that don't make no sense. Go to Matthew
the 24th chapter and read verse 6 and 8.
And ye shall hear of wars and rumors of
wars. See that ye be not troubled, for
all these things must come to pass, but
the end is not
yet. Verse eight. All these are the
beginning of sorrows.
Now, what's this got to do with birth
pains? Apparently, they got the wrong
scripture. So, I don't know what you're
talking about. That have nothing to do
with birth
pains. Okay. Now the first part of it is
at coming of Jesus will his when his
feet touch Mount
Si would uh it be us or the angel the
first thing is is not mount si that's
when his feet touch the mount of olives
right and the answer yeah both us and
the angels going to be with it go to
Matthew's 26th chapter and read verse 31
Then said Jesus unto them, "All ye shall
be offended because of me this night.
For it is written, I will smite the
shepherd, and the sheep of the flock
shall be scattered."
Oh, I'm sorry. 25 and 31.
25 and 31.
When the Son of Man shall come in his
glory, and all the holy angels with him,
then shall he sit upon the throne of his
glory.
And that one let you know all the holy
angels going to come with him. Isn't
that correct? Yep. Yep. And let's go to
First Thessalonians 3 and read verse 12
and 13.
1 Thessalonians 3.
And the Lord spake unto you. And the
Lord spake you to increase and abound in
love one toward another, and towards all
men, even as we do towards you, to the
end. He may establish your hearts
unblameable in holiness before God, even
our father, at the coming of our Lord
Jesus Christ with all his saints. Mhm.
So the saints, so the saints are the
people that's going to be raised and
changed during the first
resurrection. They going to come with
it. And also the angels going to come
with it. So you going to have two sets
that's coming. The angels, which is the
armies in heaven, and the people that
are going to be in the first
resurrection and that going to be
changed and raised in the first
resurrection. That's all I have to say.
All right. The other second part,
whoever asked that, you need to go back
and relook and and look at that. Maybe
you got the wrong scripture cuz it don't
have nothing to do with birth pain.
That's all I have to say. All
right. So, we're going to continue to
move right along with our next question.
Next question. Sandra Allen asks in
Deuteronomy 16 verse1 16
concerning the feast. Does this apply to
women also when there are no males in
the household?
All right. Deuteronomy
16-16. Does this apply to the women also
if there are no males in the home?
Brother Dre, what you say? Let's go read
Deuteronomy 16 and 16 and then we'll
we'll answer that question. Go ahead,
brother. Three times in a year shall all
the males appear before the Lord thy God
in the place which he shall choose in
the feast of unleven bread and in the
feast of weeks and in the feast of
tabernacles. And they shall not appear
before the Lord empty. Verse 17. Every
man shall give as he is able, according
to the blessing of the Lord thy God,
which he hath given thee. So, this right
here is talking about men, but it's not
exclusive to men. Let's back up and read
verse 13. Now, go ahead. Thou shalt
observe the feast of tabernacles seven
days. After that, thou hast gathered in
thy corn and thy wine. Mhm. And thou
shall rejoice in thy feast. Thou and thy
sons and thy daughters and thy man's
servant and thy maid servant and the
Levites, the stranger and the fatherless
and the widows that are within thy
gates. And the fatherless and the
widows. Some widows will be there.
meaning that and and the fatherless they
means that they don't have a child but
they might have a
mother and they will be there. So the
mother may be heading up the house but
all is going to come but that particular
verse was talking about the man but it's
not exclusive to men because all are
going to come. It says, "Thy son and thy
daughter," the man's servant, the maid
servant, the stranger. We talking about
tabernacles three times a year. Unleaven
bread, feast of weeks, Pentecost, and
tabernacles. Now, let's go to Nehemiah.
Nehemiah 8.
Nehemiah 8. Yeah. And pick it up at
verse one. And we gonna skip from there.
Nehemiah 8 verse one. Go ahead.
2 Chronicles, Ezra, and then Nehem.
And all the people gathered themselves
together as one man into the street that
was before the Watergate, and they spake
unto Ezra the scribe, to bring the book
of the law of Moses, which the Lord have
commanded to Israel. So the Lord blessed
them to be able to bring the book of the
law, and they reading out of the book,
the things written in it. Skip down to
verse eight. Now go ahead. So they read
in the book in the law of God distinctly
and gave the sense and caused them to
understand the reading. Mhm. Go ahead.
And Nehemiah, which is
the Tashatha and Ezra, the priest of the
scribes, and the Levites that taught the
people, said unto all the people, "This
day is holy unto the Lord your God.
Mourn not nor weep." For all the people
wept when they heard the words of the
law. Now he said that to all the people,
right? So that is all inclusive. It's
not exclusive to just males, but to all
the people. Go ahead, brother. Then he
said unto them, "Go your way, eat the
fat, and drink the sweet, and send
portions unto them for whom nothing is
prepared. For this day is holy unto our
Lord. Neither be ye sorrow, for the joy
of the Lord is your strength.
Now, you could you could read all of
this, but I want you to skip down for
time's sake. I want you to uh to skip
down to verse 16. Go ahead, brother. So
the people went forth and brought them
and made themselves booth, everyone upon
the roof of his house, and in their
courts, and in the courts of the house
of God, and in the streets of the
Watergate, and in the streets of the
gates of Ephraim.
All the congregation of them that were
come again out of the captivity made
booths, and sat under the booths. For
since the days of Joshua the son of Nun,
unto that day had not the children of
Israel done so, and there was very great
gladness.
Yes. Go ahead. Also, day by day, from
the first day unto the last day, he read
in the book of the law of God, they kept
the feast seven days, and on the eighth
day was a solemn assembly according unto
the man. So we see here that they
keeping the feast but it was all of the
people but the book takes times a year
shall appear males and you shall not
appear empty. That's all I got. Yeah,
that's correct, Dre. And we know that
man is the woman's side of man. Yes,
sir. All right. Thank you for that,
brother. Hope that answered that
question as we move right on. Yes.
Moving on, Ni uh Jones have two more
questions. One, in Matthew 24 verse 22,
what does it mean for the elect's sake?
And two, what will we be doing for the 3
and a half years while we are in the
wilderness?
All right, brother Jerome, sister Ni
here want a double portion of life. Can
you help her out?
Let's go read it. Matthews 24 and 22.
And except those days should be
shortened, there shall no flesh be
saved, but for the elect's sake, those
days shall be shortened.
Okay, the elect here is primarily
talking about uh the Israelites. All
right, skip down to verse 29, read it to
31.
Immediately after the tribulation of
those days shall the sun be darkened,
and the moon shall not give her light,
and the stars shall fall from heaven,
and the powers of the heaven shall be
shaken. And then shall appear the sign
of the son of man in heaven, and then
shall all the tribes of the earth mourn,
and they shall see the son of man coming
in the clouds of heaven with power and
great glory.
He shall send his angels with a great
sound of a trumpet. And they shall
gather together his elect from the four
winds from one end of heaven to the
other. Yeah, that's primarily Israel.
They going to be gathered from all over
the world, right? And they're referred
to as the elect of God. Let's let's go
to Isaiah 45 and read verse
four.
Uh I let me make sure. I think it's 54.
Let me check.
But uh go ahead to that that because
that might be the right one. I know it
says Isaiah. I think I think that's what
you want.
You shoot out the first sentence.
Um yeah, go ahead and read it. For
Jacob, my servant's sake, and Israel, my
elect. Uhhuh. I have even called thee by
thy name. I have sain thee, though thou
hast not known me. Yeah, that's it.
Israel, mine elect. Talking about the
children of Israel. That's right. Now,
you got a uh second question. Could you
repeat that for me? Yes. What will we be
doing for the three and a half years
while we are in the wilderness?
Okay. Well, when we flee into the
wilderness, the Lord going to be
providing for us. He going to be
nourishing us. He going to be giving us
drink just like he did in the past when
the children of Israel was in the
wilderness.
And
um um when Israel get gathered to the
wilderness, they going to be brought
under the bond of the covenant. Uh it's
going to be a marriage supp. It's called
the marriage supper of the lamb. That's
going to be going on in the wilderness.
But Israel primarily going to be keeping
the covenant and the commandments of God
in that wilderness. Okay. Uh but yeah,
he going to nourish them just like he
going to do other people that flee into
the wilderness. you know, 3 and 1/2
years before the Lord come and three and
a half years after the Lord come, the
Lord going to be taking care of and
feeding them and and and bringing them
under the bond of that covenant,
especially during that gather, right, to
the wilderness. That's all I got on.
Right. Thank you for that, brother. As
we move on to our next question with a
time check. Uh, yes, the time is 811.
Cassie or Lee have two questions. One,
I've been following the teachings of the
IOG. I feel I should be paying tithes.
So, where should I send them? And two,
are Asians Hammites or Gentiles?
All right. First part of that, I've been
following the teachings of the Israel of
God. Good move. And we're gonna ask
brother Julius to take it from there.
Yeah. Yeah, you pay your tithe. You can
send your tithe to the headquarters,
Israel of God headquarters, Riverdale,
Illinois. Uh they'll make sure that you
get uh a statement at the end of the
year. And uh your second question, are
Asians, Hammites, or Gentiles? Asians
are
Gentiles. We have to I'm going help you
out on your own. You can go to your
encyclopedia or you could do your Google
Earth. You could type in
Eurasia. This right
here probably you can't probably see it.
You can't probably see it that good, but
this is a ancient map of Eurasia, which
uh is central, which is Western,
Central, and Eastern Europe. They are
Gentiles. They are Hamites are your
African peoples. Let me show you what
I'm talking about. Let's go to Genesis
the 10th
chapter. We we've heard uh most of our
lives we heard if you're not a Jew,
you're a Gentile. That is an
error. And we f to read it right now.
Graing this error out. Genesis 10, we
going 1 to 5. Tenzel.
Now these are the generation of the sons
of Noah. Shem, Ham, and Japheth. And Ham
and Jacob. Japheth. Out of these three
sons of Noah was the whole earth
overspread.
And if you don't if you don't come out
of these three, you don't exist. Right.
Go ahead. And unto them were sons born
after the flood. Yes. The sons of
Japheth, Gomer, and Magog and Madiah and
Javan and Tubal and Mek and Tyrus.
Uhhuh. The sons of Gomer,
Ashenaz, and Rimath, and
Togamar, the sons of Javin, Alishi, and
Tarses, Kdum, and
Dudm. By these were the owls of the
Gentiles, divided in their lands,
everyone after his tongue, after their
families, and their nations. So these
are the people of all of
Europe, Western, Central and Eastern. So
Asia, Asians are gentile. They are all
grouped together like Russia, right?
Like China, like Iran, Iraq, India, all
these are people are grouped together.
These are Eastern Asians.
And remember one of those ancient name
was Asia Minor which included Turkey. So
everything that was eastern of the
Euphrates River was considered the
Orient or East. So the Asians are
Gentiles. They just live on uh they just
live on the eastern side of Europe. I
hope that helps says Cornell.
All right. Yes, sir. And I just wanted
to go back to the first part of that
question about how she said she been
following the Israel of God. Like I say,
good move. And where you can send your
ties to, you got a pen. It's the Israel
of
God
520 West 138th Street, Riverdale,
Illinois 60827.
Thank you, brother. All right. Thank you
for tuning in, sister. and um may your
faith increase. All right, we're going
to move on to our next question. Next
question. Ar uh Edward Barber have a few
questions. Uh he says, "Is the father
and Jesus Christ the tree of life? Is
there helpful scripture to help us keep
the commandments and laws? And how is
judgment day going to work?
All right, pretty much in that question,
but we're going to ask the uh guest
caller to share some light.
Well, the first thing is the father and
Jesus can give
life. What the tree of life that was in
the garden of Eden and that we have been
dealing with is
Jesus. And we'll show you why. Go into
St. John the 5th chapter and read verse
37. And the Father himself which have
sent me have borne witness of me. Ye
have neither heard his voice at any time
nor seen his shape.
So now you ain't never seen the father
or heard his voice. So all we ever dealt
with was Jesus. So when when the Bible
talks about the tree of life, that's
talking about Jesus. Yep. Now, and this
other stuff is, you know, uh uh uh as
far as uh uh help the scripture help us
keep the commandments. First thing is
you got to obey Jesus. Go to Matthew's
19th
chapter and read verse 16 and 17.
And behold, one came and said unto him,
What good, Master, what good thing shall
I do that I might have eternal life? And
he said unto him, Why callst thou me
good? There is none good but one, and
that is God. But if thou will enter into
life, keep the commandments.
Now, that should be effortful when you
go and see what Jesus gave to answer. If
you want to get eternal life, keep the
commandments. M and uh if you don't keep
the commandments, maybe this will deter
you a little bit because cuz if you
don't keep the commandments, if you're
in the book of life, you going to get
blotted out of it. And if you get
blotted out of the book of life, then
this what's going to happen to you. Read
Revelation 20 and 15.
And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life was cast into the lake
of fire.
Now that ought to give you some
incentive. You know, you keep the
commandments cuz you don't want to end
up in the lake of fire. And as far as
judgment is concerned, how does that go?
Simple. The Lord going to look at your
works and and uh uh uh and they they
found lacking, you going to end up in
the lake of fire because you going to be
judged according to the words that's
written in this book.
And if you come up short, you going to
end up in the lake of fire. Just back up
and let's read just a little of it.
Okay. Yep. Start at verse 11. 20
Revelation 20 and 11.
And I saw a great white throne, him that
sat on it, from whose face the earth and
the heaven fled away, and there was
found no place for them. And I saw the
dead, small and great, stand before God,
and the books were open, and another
book was open, which is the book of
life. And the dead were judged out of
those things which were written in the
books, according to their
works. And the sea gave up the dead.
That's how that's how judgment work. The
Lord, the dead and the living going to
be judged according to those things that
are written in the in these books. This
is the Bible.
according to your
works. So if you don't if your works
come up lacking, you going to end up in
the liquor fire. That's all I have to
say. Yep. You don't want no parts of
that. So it's time to get to
work. All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Barber still says, "Didn't
Joseph and Mary hide with baby Jesus in
Egypt as well and was not detected?"
All right, brother Dre, what you say?
Uh, that's brother Jerome.
Um, if we go to um Matthew's the second
chapter, it's going to answer that
question straight out. So, let's go to
Matthews the 2
chapter and pick it up at verse 11 and
read it to the
15. Matthew 2 and 11. Yeah. And when
they were and when they were come into
the house, they saw the young child with
Mary his mother and fell down and
worshiped him. And when they had opened
their treasures, they presented unto him
gifts, gold, and frankincense, and myrr.
And being warned of God in a dream that
they should not return to Herod, they
departed into their own country another
way. And when they were departed,
behold, the angel of the Lord appeared
to Joseph in a dream, saying, "Arise and
take the young child and his mother and
flee into Egypt." So he telling u the
angel who's warning the parents Mary and
Joseph to take the young child and flee
into Egypt. Go ahead and be thou there
until I bring thee work. Here I will
seek the young child to destroy
him. And when he arose, he took the
young child and his mother by night and
departed into
Egypt. and was there unto the death of
Herod, that it might be fulfilled which
was spoken of the Lord by the prophet,
saying, "Out of Egypt have I called my
son." Yeah, that's all I got.
All right, thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question. As we
move on to our next one, next one. Kim
Noel asks, "Will people that don't
worship God, that get killed for not
taking the mark, be in the first
resurrection, or will they have to be
judged in the second resurrection?"
All right, guess caller.
Well, only the people that worship God
is going to be in the first
resurrection. Those are the saints.
That's why we're talking about when the
Lord come, we're going to be said two
women are grinded at the meal. One's
taken and the other one's left. That's
when we meet him in the air. The one
that's left is the one that don't
worship God. Right? And the other part
of this is yes, they will be
judged. Go to Revelation 20 and read 11
and 13.
And I saw a great white throne, and him
that sat on it, from whose face the
earth and the heavens fled away, and
there was found no place for them. And
the sea gave up the dead which were in
it, and death and hell delivered up the
dead which were in them, and they were
judged every man according to their
works.
So that's So yes, that's the way it's
going. Whether he worship God or not,
he's still going to be judged. And if
he's found
worthy, he will enter into the kingdom
as God. But if he found worthy unworthy,
he going to end up in the lake of fire.
Now, if he did not worship God, whether
he received a mark or not, he going to
end up in the lake of fire. That's point
blank. That's all I have to say. All
right. Hope that answers your question
as we move on to our next next one. One
Mona says, "Are women not to wear pants
at all?"
Women can wear pants. Sure they can. But
um we ask that when you come to the
worship service at the Israel of God, we
ask that all women wear dresses or
skirts, modest apparel. Or if you
participate in the feast or something
that's dealing with worship for God, we
ask that you wear a dress or a skirt.
But outside of that, um yeah, women are
allowed to wear pants. Anything else,
guess call them?
Well, the whole thing is cuz there ain't
nothing that says that uh that said they
can or cannot because the scriptures
somebody can find that right quick where
the Lord said a woman should not wear
that which pertainth to a man. We'll
read that right quick. Somebody find it.
All right. Search mode for that. Of
course.
Uh Deuteromy 22. Tanzanel 22 and let's
pick it up at verse
five. I believe that's
it. The woman shall not wear that which
pertainth unto a man, neither sh a man
put on a woman's garment, for all that
do so are abomination unto the Lord thy
God.
Now when I look at that when it say
should not wear that which pertain to a
man it now who said that pants would
pertain to a
man there ain't no scripture that say it
is but because of
confusion the uh uh uh the
uh deacons years ago passed a law that
we couldn't be definitive out of the
Bible but it was a bylaw that the
deacons
are passed years ago that any woman that
come and
participate in the
service have to wear a dress or a
skirt, have the head covered and uh uh
so the uh uh so sure you know we don't
know what pertain to a pan. So there
ain't nothing that said that pants
pertain to a man.
So like your brother say, if you going
to participate in certain things
spiritually at at the Israel of God,
then you uh uh uh you wear a dress or a
skirt. All
right. So we hope that answers your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Barbara Still asks, "Do you
have to get baptized to become a member
of IOG?
Um, no. It would be a wise idea. I mean,
in order to be in the family of God,
you're going to have to get
baptized.
So, anybody else want to add?
Okay. You got to get baptized and come
up under the
covenant, under the blood of Jesus.
That's correct. Yep. So, it would be a
wise move to do that because uh hey,
Jesus was baptized and he led the way.
So, all of us who believe in him and
serve him out of a pure heart should
follow in his
steps. All
right, Sister Deborah, we're going to
move on to our next one. Is this uh I
think we'll leave this one to the panel
number four. The next one. Yeah. Uh
yeah, a couple of them. So Sai Amaru
Israel asks, "Is it
biblically for a woman to have her tubes
tied or for a man to have a
vaccine if you're if you have a lot of
kids? Is it bib is it okay biblically
for a woman to have her tubes tied or
for a man to have a
vasectomy if you have a lot of kids.
All right. Well, we know
um one of the things that God told Adam
and Eve, why don't we go there to
Genesis 1 and then we'll open it up to
the pal.
Genesis 1. Pick it up at 27. Yes sir.
So God created man in his own image, in
the image of God created he him. Male
and female created he them. And God
blessed them. And God said unto them,
"Be fruitful, and multiply, and
replenish the earth, and subdue it, and
have dominion over the fish of the sea,
and over the fowls of the air, and over
every living thing that moveth upon the
earth."
Okay. When we look at that, that's all
we
have.
So, we can't answer that question. We
can only leave you what God had written.
Be fruitful and multiply and replenish
the earth. Whatever you do other than
that, you on your own.
That's right.
All
right. So, we're gonna move on to our
next question. also open to the panel.
Sister Derek, yes. All day production
wants you to help them
understand God will reather all Israel
after the war of
Armageddon. And is there a remnant of
Jews that will be gathered before the
war of Armageddon or are they in Israel
now that will be fighting also in this
war? And Zechariah 14 verse14 is given.
All right. Why don't we go there? Read
that tanzan and open up to the town.
Zechariah 14 and
14. And Judah also shall fight at
Jerusalem. and the wealth of all the
heathens round about should be gathered
together, gold and silver and apparel in
great
abundance. Why don't you back up to 14
and one?
Behold, the day of the Lord cometh, and
thy spoils shall be divided in the midst
of thee. But I will gather all nations
against Jerusalem to battle, and the
city shall be taken, and the houses
rifled, and the women ravished, and half
of the city shall go forth into
captivity, and the residue of the people
shall not be cut off from the city.
Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations as when he fought
in the day of battle. And his feet shall
stand in that day upon the Mount of
Olives, which is before Jerusalem on the
east. And the Mount of Olives shall
cleave in the midst thereof toward the
east and toward the west. There shall be
a very great valley, and half of the
mountain shall remove toward the north,
and half of it toward the south. And ye
shall flee towards the to the valley of
the mountain, for the valley of the
mountain shall reason to Asel. Yeah, ye
shall flee like as he fled from before
the earthquakes in the days of Uzziah,
king of Judah. And the Lord my God shall
come and all the saints with thee.
Now skip down and read verse N.
And the Lord shall be king over all the
earth. In that day shall there be one
Lord and his name one.
So now
everything after that after the coming
of the Lord everything that like like
the scriptures you just read that's all
after the Lord is back on the earth now.
But before any Israelites get to the
land they got to go somewhere else place
someplace else first. Let's go into
Ezekiel the 20th chapter and read start
reading at verse
35. And I will bring you into the
wilderness of the people, and there
would I plead with you face to face.
Like as I pleaded with your fathers in
the wilderness of the land of Egypt, so
will I plead with you, sayeth the Lord
God. And I will cause you to pass under
the rod. And I will bring you into the
bond of the covenant. And I will purge
out from among you the rebels, and them
that transgress against me, and I will
bring them forth out of the country
where they sjourn, and they shall not
enter into the land of Israel, and ye
shall know that I am the Lord.
Now, so the people that have you got
sure you got some Israelites that's uh
uh uh that's in the land, but then the
Lord when he come, he's going to flatten
the land, right? He going to drive
everybody else out of the
land. And now when he start gathering
Israel, Israel is going to have to go
through the wilderness.
And in the wilderness, once they get to
the wilderness, they're going to be
brought into the barn of the
covenant. And the ones that found
lacking, they going to be purged. He's
going to purge the rebels, and they
shall not enter into the
land. So
now, anybody's in there now. The Lord is
going to run them all out. Israel,
Gentile, and
whatever. And he going to bring Israel
into the land. He go into the
wilderness. going to have him there 3
and 1/2 years and when he come up out of
there he is going to go into the temple
which the immortals going to be built
Zerubbabel and his people going to build
a temple who know won't be nobody in the
land and the people that's going to be
doing fighting that's spoken in
Zechariah the 14th chapter these are
people that was
returned after the war of
Armageddon after the time that Jesus
brought him into the wilderness and
purged them. That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question there. Go ahead, brother. And
and if all all day production, if you
really read that 14th verse more clear,
it it wasn't even talking about um the
people or Israel being gathered. Read
that verse one more time and it'll be
more clear. Read it one more time.
Oh 14 to 14. Yeah, they're not talking
about gathering people or
Israelites. Go ahead and read that verse
again. And Judah also shall fight at
Jerusalem. And the wealth of all the
heathens round about shall be gathered
together. See, that's what's going to be
gathered together in that verse. The
wealth of all the heathen going to be
gathered. the silver, the peril, and
abundance.
The nations.
Yeah, that's all I can say. All
right, Sister Deborah, we're going to
move on. I believe we're going to new
territory now, right? Yes. We are now
into tonight's Q&A for May the 14, 2025.
She is Hebrew living
says Christ spoke in
parables. Can that be equated to
speaking in tongues? Most people had no
knowledge or understanding of what he
was saying. Even his disciples, he
always said that those who have ears
hear. All
right, let's open that up to the panel.
I'm going to say
no. You got two different definitions
going on here. Tongues is another
language. Parables is an earthly story
with a spiritual or heavenly meaning.
Let's go to Matthew 13, brother Tanzil.
Matthew the 13th
chapter. Two different definitions.
Matthew 13 and pick it up at verse one
and read Tanzel. Go ahead. The same day
when Jesus out of the house and set by
the
seaside and great multitudes was
gathered together unto him, so that he
went into a ship and sat. The whole
multitude stood on the shore. Go ahead.
And he spake many things unto them in
parables, saying, He spoke many things
unto them in parables, earthly stories
that had spiritual meanings. You can
read the rest of it on your own. Skip
down uh to verse uh uh well read uh it's
talking about the the parable of the
swer of
seed. Skip down to verse 9 and read.
Who have ears to hear, let him hear. Go
ahead. And the disciples came and said
unto him, why speakest thou unto them in
parables? What did Jesus say? And he
answered and said unto them, because it
is given unto you to know the mysteries
of the kingdom of heaven, but to them it
is not given. But to them is not given
at this time. It's for the disciples for
you to understand these things. He's not
speaking in tongues. He's speaking in
parables. When you read the whole
chapter, he will straighten and read
this whole chapter. He will tell you
exactly what he is saying. He interprets
the uh the
parables. It is about the sewer seed.
You sow the word of God. Some hear, some
don't, and so on and so forth. So, no,
this has nothing to do with speaking in
tongues. It is uh parables,
spiritual, an earthly uh message that
has a spiritual meaning. Anybody else
want to add to that? Why don't you read
the
parable of the swords of the sea? All
right, let's pick it.
Yes, sir. And then what when he's asked,
let him explain it. Pick it up. Verse
three again. Tenzel.
And he spake many things unto them in
parables, saying, Behold, a swer went
forth to sow. And when he had sold some
seeds, fell by the wayside, and the
fowls came and devoured them up. But
some fell upon stony places where they
had not much earth, and forth with they
sprung up, because they had no deepness
of earth.
And when the sun was dry was was up,
they were scorched. And because they had
no root, they withered away. And some
fell among thorns. And the thorns sprung
up and choked them. But others fell into
good ground and brought forth fruit,
some
100fold, some 60fold, some 30fold. But
who have ears to hear, let him hear. who
that have ears to hear, let him let them
hear. Let them hear. So now he's talking
about a a a parable uh an earthly story
that has a spiritual meaning. Sisters
and brothers, this what these uh uh
verse 18, you want to hear the answer
18.
Let Jesus answer. He breathe.
And he answered and said unto them
because it is G. You want me to skip
down a little bit or
explain the
ter verse 18.
Uh Julius 15 might be better about the
pair
of pick it up at 15 and then we'll read
down to what Julius say. Go ahead.
For this people heart is waxed gross,
and their ears are dull of hearing.
Their eyes they have closed, lest at any
time they shall see with their eyes, and
hear with their ears, and should
understand with their heart, and should
be converted, and I shall heal them.
That's your spiritual eyes, your
spiritual ear. Go ahead. That's right.
But blessed are your eyes, for they see,
and your ears, for they hear. Go ahead,
brother. For verily I say unto you, that
many prophets and righteous men have
desired to see those things which ye
see, and have not seen them, and to hear
those things which ye hear, and have not
heard them. Go ahead. But hear ye
therefore the parable of the sword. When
anyone hear the word of the kingdom, and
understandeth it not, then cometh the
wicked one, and catcheth away that which
was sown in his heart. This is he which
receiveth seed by the
wayside. But he that receiveth deceive
in stony places, the same as he that
hearth the word and an aron with joy
receive it not. Yet have he not rooted
in himself, but doeth for a while. For
when tribulation or persecution ariseth
because of the word by and by he is
offended. He also that received the seed
among the thorns, he of is he that
heareth the word, and the cares of the
world, and the deceitfulness of riches,
choke the word, and he becometh
unfruitful.
James,
but he that receiveth seed into the good
ground is he that heareth the word and
understand it, which also beareth fruit
and bringeth forth some 100fold, Psalm
60, Psalm 30.
So
now all it mean is like like Junior said
the Lord uh is is spiritual. He's using
something like a metaphor. He using uh
uh the uh uh uh seed as the word of God.
Like some people hear it, they all
happy, but soon as a little drama fall
on them, they run away from it. Some
people hear it and they like it. But
then it come the time they have to
choose between the word of God and
money. So they choose money. So it got
nothing to do with speaking in tongue.
It got something to do with your belief.
That's right.
Thank you.
We uh we read 1 Corinthians 14 real
quick.
Right.
14 and 22.
1 Corinthians 14 and 22. Yes, sir.
Wherefore tongues are for a sign, but
not to them that believe, but to them
that believe
not. But prophesy serves not for them
that believe not, but for them which
believe.
So verse 21 says, what in the law it is
written, with men of other tongues and
other lips will I speak unto this
people, and yet for for all that they
will, they not hear. Let me read that
again. And yet for all that will they
not hear me, said the Lord. So they
hearing the word of God, but they not
they not obeying it, right? For a sign
for for not to them that believe, but to
them that believe not. And that sign, if
you hear something being spoken in a
language that that person don't speak,
that's definitely a sign. Mhm.
Yep. All right. Yep. Good add- on for
that. Sister Deborah, wasn't there a
second part of that question? Uh, that
was it. The
question that was it. All right. Cuz I
know about disciples, but
uh understanding what he was saying.
Even his uh she just added that the
disciples didn't understand a lot of
what was said. Also, it wasn't a
question. She just added that in. Okay.
So, the next question. Hold on one
second. Deborah, guess.
But I want them to
understand he was speaking in the same
language that they spoke in. Yep. It's
just they didn't believe it. Yes. Had
nothing to
do. Yeah. That's all. All right. Hope
that answered your question. Time check
as we move into the next. Yes, the time
is 8:45. Moving on. Be alert wants you
to explain Daniel 8 verse 23. What are
dark sentences?
Daniel 8 and 23.
Yes. Let's go to
Tanz people. Uh uh go read it then and
and and then we'll deal with it. Go read
it.
Daniel 8:23.
Yeah. In the latter time.
And in the latter time of their kingdom,
when the transgressors are come to the
fool, a king of fear is continents and
understanding dark sentences shall stand
up.
Now when the people look at dark s, they
think evil. No, that don't have nothing
to do with evil. that have to do with
stuff that other people don't
understand.
Right? A dark s right a dark sentence
right now to the whole world is that God
is creating man. God created man to
become God. Dark sentence.
Yeah. Another dark sentence is that God
is going to bring the kingdom the father
and Jesus going to rule his earth for a
thousand years. People talking about
going to heaven. Another dark sinners is
that it said in Revelation 21st chapter
that the kingdom of God is going to
come. In fact, go to Revelation 21 and
start reading that 21 to about five. At
one from 1 to 5. Revelation 21. This is
the darkest sinners of all of them. And
he that sit upon the
throne. Revelation 21 and five. Right.
Start at verse one. One. And I saw a new
heaven and a new earth. For the first
heaven and first earth were passed away,
and there was no more sea. And I saw
John, and I, John, saw the holy city,
New Jerusalem, coming down from God out
of heaven, prepared as a bride adorned
for her husband. And I heard a great
voice out of heaven, saying, Behold, the
tabernacle of God is with men, and he
will dwell with them, and they shall be
his people, and God himself shall be
with them, and be their God.
And
God, listen, that's a dark sentence
right there. Everybody's talking about
you going to heaven, but right there,
God say he's coming to earth. You ain't
going up there to be with him. He say
he's coming down to be with man. And
that's what the book say.
Anybody and anybody that understand that
understand a dark sentence. In other
words, this a sentence that's hid from
everybody else. Not that it's hidden in
the book. is just because they have been
taught wrong. And when you hear any
truth, it's a dark sentence. Like Jesus
going to sit on David's throne. How many
people know that? And David's throne is
in in Jerusalem on this earth.
Not a lot.
That's a dark sentence.
Okay. Have nothing to do with evil. Have
to do with knowledge that's hidden from
the average people and from the world
because of their disbelief. Right.
That's all. Yeah. They call it dark, but
it's light.
They can't.
But the folk going understand that.
That's why they going to get thrown in
the lake of fire.
Yep. All right. Hope that answered your
question there. As we move on to our
next one, moving on. most love asked in
numbers
19 14 and 15 concerning being unclean
for touching dead bodies and having
ashes in your house. Are those laws done
away with according to Hebrews 10
verse1?
No. No, they are not. They still good
for the day. guest caller.
Go to Hebrews 10 and1 and read it. Well,
go to Numbers first and read it. Yeah.
Numbers
19 and read that verse 14 and 15 talking
about when someone
dies. This is the law. When a man dieth
in a tent, all that come into the tent
and all that is in the tent shall be
unclean seven days. And every open
vessel which have no covering bound upon
it is unclean.
And
whosoever gohead
touchth one that is slain with a sword
in an open field or a dead body or a
bone of a man or a grave shall be
unclean seven days.
Okay. Now let's go and show you what
Jesus terh terminated. Let's go to
Hebrews the 10th chapter.
Read verse one and then skip
down. Read verse one first.
For the law having a shadow of good
things to come and not the very image of
the things can never with those
sacrifices which they offer year by year
continually make the comers there unto
perfect.
Now this talking about this and all the
law of animal sacrifice. They can't make
it right. Why? Skip down to verse four
and read it. For it is not possible that
the blood of bulls and of goats should
take away sins.
Wherefore, when he cometh into the
world, look, that's the whole thing. The
blood of bulls and goats couldn't take
away sin. Right?
When Jesus come, he stoan.
That's why our body had to be prepared
for him. So no, they still in order.
Uncleanliness is still in
order. Jesus terminated animal sacrifice
that was created because of
sin. Death is not sin. Dead body is not
sin. That is condition that makes you
unclean, but it is not
sin. That's all I have to say.
All
right, as we continue to move on to our
next question.
Moving on. John Noel says, "A while
back, IOG will allow tassels back in the
church."
But it's my understanding that one of
the 613 commandments in the Torah was to
wear them.
6 and how many?
613 commandments in the Torah was to
wear them.
Guess what did he say? The OG what?
Would allow castles back in the church?
You saying? You talking about fringes?
That's what it sounds like. Yeah. The
little things
kind of look like it got a ball on it
and string hanging from it. Those types
of things.
Well, you know, you know, uh uh I I know
what the Bible say about fringes. Sure,
the Lord uh uh uh told us to wear
fringes, but let's tell let's let's go
and look at the reason why. Will
somebody find that and read where this
man was picking up sticks on the sand?
Numbers 15.
Okay. And start
where? Pick it up in verse 32.
Go ahead.
And while the children of Israel were in
the wilderness, they found a man that
gathered sticks upon the Sabbath day.
And they that found him gathering sticks
brought him unto Moses and Aaron and to
all the congregation. And they put him
in war, because it was not declared what
shall be done to him. And the Lord said
unto the man shall be surely put to
death. All the congregation shall stone
him with stones without the
camp. And all the congregation brought
him without the camp and stone with
stones. And he died as the Lord
commanded Moses.
And the Lord spake in the Moses, speak
unto the children of Israel, and bid
them that they make them franges in the
borders of their garments throughout
their generations, and that they put
upon the fringes fring fringe of the
borders a ribbon of blue. And it shall
be unto you for friends that ye may look
upon it and remember all the
commandments of the Lord and do them and
that ye seek not after your own heart
and your own eyes after which ye use to
be to
go that ye may remember and do all my
commandments and be holy unto your God.
Now because Israel broke the
law and the man got this man got stoned
to death, the Lord instituted
fringes. And the fringes was supposed to
remind you to keep God's commandments in
his laws. Didn't work. Then the Lord
added another law, animal sacrifice,
because the fringes didn't work. But
then the animal sacrifice didn't work.
So, Israel still didn't keep the law.
So, the Lord say he going to do
something else. He going to make a new
covenant. Go to Jeremiah 31 and start
reading at verse 31.
Jeremiah 31 and 31.
Behold, the days come, sayeth the Lord,
that I will make a new covenant with the
house of Israel, and with the house of
Judah, but not according to the covenant
that I made with their fathers, in the
day that I took them by the hand, to
bring them out of the land of Egypt,
which my covenant they break, although I
was a husband unto them, said the Lord.
But this shall be the covenant that I
will make with the house of Israel after
those days, sayeth the Lord. I will put
my law in their inward parts and write
and write it in their hearts and will be
their God and they should be my people
and they shall teach no more every man
his
neighbor. That's once once you get into
your heart them nobody going to have to
teach you. But what he said he going to
make a new
covenant. What he going to do with the
same laws? He going to put them in your
mind. That's right. Because the fringes
the animal sacrifice didn't work. But
you going to put it in your mind. So
when you get ready to uh uh sneak into
somebody's back door, you going to have
it in your mind. The law says, "Thou
shall not commit adultery."
You see something that don't belong to
you and you want to take it, that law in
your mind says, "Thou shalt not steal."
And so the only reason that the elders
in the Israel of God allowed people to
come with their fringes is because we
know that the fringes are not our
covenant and they ain't
necessary. We allow them to come so they
can learn what the truth is that they
are under a new covenant. And the new
covenant does not require you to wear
fringes. It require you remember his
law. Right. Yes sir.
In other words, the elders allowed them
to come so they can get educated and
stop running around telling people that
fringes is our culture. Because if it
was our culture, then Paul would not
have been mistaken for an Egyptian.
Everybody would have known that he was a
Hebrew Israelite. Right.
That's all I got to say.
Yeah. And when you when you see tassels
sometimes as totally different tassels
can be a part of just fashion that
people have on their ponchos and things
of that nature. Right. That's the only
that's only significant of you.
Yeah. Yeah. All right. Is not our
never our culture.
Nope. Never was. It was a reminder to
remind you keep the commandments
which you didn't do still ain't doing
right. Okay.
All right. Hope that answered your
question sister Deborah as we are
running out of time.
Uh yes. uh be alert as in Isaiah 10 21
and 22. Is this the first return of
Israel after the Assyrian captivity?
Isaiah 10 21-22. Go ahead. Isaiah 10
vers 21 and 22.
All right, Tenzel, go ahead and then
we'll open it up. The remnant shall
return, even the remnant of Jacob unto
the mighty God. For though thy people
Israel be as the sand of the sea, yet a
remnant of them shall return, and the
consummation decree shall overflow with
righteousness, consumption.
All right, open to the pan.
Well, the remnant of Israel ain't going
to come, especially the ones that the
Syrians took out or Judah going to
return, not going to rec until Jesus
come. Go to the Deuteronomy 30 chapter
and start reading at verse
one. Deuteronomy 30 and 1.
And it shall come to pass with all these
things I come upon thee, the blessing
and the curse, which I have set before
thee, and thou shalt call them to mine
among all the nations, whether the Lord
thy God hath driven thee, and shall
return unto the Lord thy God, and shall
obey his voice, according to all that I
command thee this day, thou and thy
children with all thy heart, and with
all thy soul, that then the Lord thy God
would earn thy captivity, and have
compassion upon thee, and will return
and gather thee from all the nations,
whether the Lord thy God has scattered
thee.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. He said,
"And return and gather you from all the
nations." Isn't that what he said? And
return. That's what he said. From all
nations.
Go ahead.
If any of thine be driven out into the
outmost parts of heaven, from then will
the Lord thy God gather thee, and from
thence will he fetch
thee. And the Lord thy God will bring
thee into the land which thy fathers
possess, and thou shalt possess it, and
he will do thee good, and multiply thee
above thy fathers.
So now nobody is going to be
returned, especially the ones that the
Assyrians took out. But nobody's going
to be returned until Jesus return. Then
he's going to gather you and then you
ain't going directly to the land. You
got to go through the wilderness first.
That's all. Yeah. All right. We hope
that answered your question there,
Sister Deborah. Time check. Yes. The
time is 9:01.
All right, we have ran out of time and
we want to thank everybody from all
around the world who tuned in with us
this evening. If you submitted a
question and we have a chance to get to
it, we ask you to please don't resubmit
it. Sister Deborah, take it, put it in
rotation, and we will deal with that
question next Wednesday. So until we all
come together again, we ask you all be
safe, be blessed, stay prayed up, and
may the Lord have mercy on us all. As
brother Tanzel closes us out, our
Father, which are in heaven, hallowed be
thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven. Give
us this day our daily bread. And forgive
us of our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever in